There have been Palestinians who have protested peacefully in the past.
Why is that voice not louder? Why does that voice not have more influence here?
I would ask your producers and I would ask other mainstream media producers why they don't amplify
those voices much more. The history of Palestinian nonviolent movement is robust and far greater than
any of these episodes, and yet it doesn't get the same amount of attention. In 2018,
Palestinian youth in Gaza organized the largest civil society protest. 20,000 to 40,000 Palestinians
marched peacefully every single week in the Great March of Return, demanding the right to return to
their homelands in an end of the siege. They were shot down like birds by Israeli snipers.
Mum, there was no coverage of them. The boycott divestment sanctions movement takes inspiration
from the anti-apartheid movement against South Africa, and yet that is maligned and castigated
as being violent, even though that is the quintessential form of nonviolent resistance.
In 2011 and 12, civilians boarded flotillas to break the siege on Gaza, and they were commandeered
by eight Israeli naval commandos. Where was the coverage of that? This is not about how Palestinians,
whether or not they resist peacefully or violently. This is about the right of Palestinians to resist at
all, and it really is the responsibility of media, of international diplomatic capital.